Guide to the Eltinge-Lord Family Papers (Peter Eltinge Papers), 1856-1871 RL.00361
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
There are a number of scattered items in the Lord Division connected with the Civil War. They include an order limiting the correspondence of naval personnel with members of the press (records of the Chillocothe, orders), letters announcing the formation of a veterans' organization known as the Mississippi Squadron Association (personal letter), a piece of stationery bearing the Confederate flag (Confederate papers), and a critical evaluation of General Banks by Mary Lord after George had been ordered up the Red River (personal letters, copies).
Chillicothe (Ship); United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Campaigns; Southern States -- Race relations; United States. Army -- African American troops; Ozark (Ship); Mississippi River; Osage (Ship); Georgia -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Merchants -- Tennessee -- Memphis; Cotton -- Marketing; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Naval operations; Freedmen -- Southern States; Red River Expedition, 1864; Reconstruction; Soldiers -- United States -- Correspondence; Southern States -- Economic conditions; United States. Army. New York Infantry Regiment, 156th (1862-1865); United States. Army. Dept. of the Gulf; United States. Navy. Mississippi Squadron; United States. Navy -- Officers -- Correspondence; Eltinge, Peter, ca. 1842-1877; Eltinge, Peter, ca. 1842-1877; United States. Army -- Officers -- Correspondence; Lord, George P., ca. 1842-1866
- Eltinge Division
  - Correspondence, 1856-1864 August 29 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1864 Sept. 2-1871 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence (typescripts), 1856-1871 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence (typescripts), 1864-1865 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence (typescripts), 1865-1871 (Box 5)
  - Scrapbook (xerographic reproduction) (Box 5)
  - Legal Papers, 1864-1865 and undated (Box 6)
  - Miscellany, 1865-1866 and undated (Box 6)
  - Clippings, 1863-1864 (Box 6)
  - Photograph (Box 6)
- Lord Division
  - Personal Letters, 1862-1867 and undated (Box 7)
  - Personal Letters (copies), 1862-1868 and undated (Box 7)
  - Records of the U.S.S. Chillicothe
    - Official Correspondence, 1863-1864 (Box 8)
    - Official Correspondence, 1865-1867 and undated (Box 9)
    - Reports of the Master at Arms, 1863-1865 (Box 10)
    - Yeoman's Reports, 1863-1865 (Box 10)
    - Surgeon's Reports, 1863- 1865 (Box 11)
    - Daily Coal Reports, 1864-1865 (Box 12)
    - Engineer's Monthly Returns, 1864 (Box 12)
    - Gunner's Monthly Reports, 1863-1865 (Box 12)
    - Carpenter's Reports, 1863-1865 (Box 12)
    - Ordnance Reports, 1863-1865 (Box 12)
    - Statements that boxes brought aboard the Chillicothe contained no spirituous liquors, 1863-1865 (Box 12)
    - Orders, 1863-1865 and undated (Box 13)
    - Commercial Papers, 1863-1865 and undated (Box 13)
    - Miscellany, 1863-1865 and undated (Box 13)
  - Records of the U.S.S. Ozark, 1864-1865 (Box 13)
  - Records of the U.S.S. Osage, 1863 and undated (Box 14)
  - Oaths of Allegiance, 1864-1865 (Box 14)
  - Printed Material, 1863-1865 (Box 14)
  - Volume: Logbook of Orders and Cotton Shipments, 1864 (Box 14)
  - Miscellany, 1864-1865 and undated (Box 14)
  - Confederate Papers, 1862-1865 (Box 14)
  - Clippings, 1861-1862 and undated (Box 14)
  - Pictures (Box 14)
- Oversize Materials, 1864-1866
  - Memphis Daily Post, 1866 August 17 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - The New Paltz Times, 1864 June 3 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - The New Paltz Times, 1866 August 31 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - The Southern Illustrated Times, 1865 November 24 (Oversize-folder 1)